Hi everyone, welcome.
Today we're gonna talk about the Web
data.
What they represent, what kind of
assumptions you're making when you
turn a website into
a dataset.
So the Web Data Lecture is gonna
differ slightly from an API lecture.
APIs and scraping are two different
ways of solving the same problem.
One can do it at scale, but they
operate in very
different engine strengths.
So as you're listening to this, I
want you to keep in mind to yourself
what kind of structure
does the Web give me and what kind
of structure do I
have to do that myself.
Let's start with why the Web matters
in the first place.
A huge amount of social and
political data is public,
continuously updated,
highly heterogeneous,
and often poorly documented.
And these features are exactly the
Web's such a powerful data source.
The most important line in this
slide is the last one.
The Web is often the first place
social behavior appears.
Organizations publish information
online long before they formalize
into reports, APIs or
databases.
That includes political movements,
advocacy groups, professional
organizations, local
governments, and sometimes even
extremists or front groups.
So if you're studying emerging
behavior, something new,
something in flux, the Web
is often where you'll see it first.
But the tradeoff is that early
signals are messy, and that
messiness is not accidental.
This slide captures the core
conceptual difference between Web
data and API data.
Websites are built from
humans, not from analysis.
They're designed to be read,
skimmed, scrolled,
and navigated visually.
They're not designed to be queried,
validated, or joint.
So that leads us to
the three problems.
First, structure is irregular.
Second, assumptions are hidden.
And third, access
points are fragile.
So the screen is the act of
recovering structure
from representation.
Unlike APIs where structure is
explicitly declared or enforced, Web
data requires interpretation.
They're referring structure from
layout, repetition, and
placement of the page.
And that interpretive
step is unavoidable.
It's also where most
gravy errors come from.
So data appear on the Web
in many different forms.
Sometimes they're static HTML pages.
Sometimes they're
embedded in tables.
Sometimes they're hidden
in PDFs or CSV downloads.
And sometimes they're rendered
dynamically with JavaScript.
And last, sometimes they'll exist in
our cat snapshots.
So what matters
most is not the format.
It's why the data are there.
The key idea here is that the most
useful Web data are
incidental, not intentional.
The site was not built
to give you a dataset.
It was built to communicate
something to an audience.
Scraping is about extracting signal
from those communication artifacts.
That means that the data always
reflect the design choices about
what matters, what is
emphasized, and what's ignored.
So now let's talk about HTML itself,
but conceptually, not technically.
HTML is a markup language.
It defines document structure.
It organizes content hierarchically.
And it relies on
nesting rather than meaning.
HTML tells you what
exists, not what it means.
There is no variable called date.
There is no column called
organization name.
There are only elements placed next
to each other in a
particular location.
So meaning is something you must
impose when you decide that a
repeated pattern corresponds
to a variable.
That's why Scrapy is not just
parsing text, it's interpretation.
So HTML is a trade.
What does that mean?
Elements contain other elements.
You have a parent-child relationship
and sibling relationships, and
position the tree
conveys meaning.
So this is critical.
Two elements of the same tag can
mean completely different things
depending on where they appear
in the tree.
Scrapy is essentially tree traversal
plus pattern matching.
You're asking questions like what
structure repeats, what is always
nested inside what,
what elements appear
together and across pages.
So let's start thinking this way.
Scrapy becomes
systematic instead of mysterious.
So the building blocks
that you work with are simple.
Tags are like div, pa, table.
We've attributes
like class ID and href.
And then we have text nodes.
So the most important idea in this
line is that meaning is inferred
from repetition location.
So one div tells you nothing, but 50
identical div is in the same
position across pages,
so it should tell you something.
Repetition is what turns
presentation into data.
So scraping is a
pattern recognition.
Good scraping relies on repeat
structure, stable attributes and
predictable nesting.
So you're reverse engineering
someone else's design decisions.
That's why scraping almost always
starts without writing code.
So you view one page source, you
scroll, you inspect, you ask what
repeats and what doesn't.
If you start coding
immediately, you're guessing.
If you start by understanding
structure, you're measuring.
So this slide shows the basics to
navigation of workflow in Python.
Conceptually, there are four steps.
First, we're going to
retrieve a page here.
Second, we're going
to parse into a tree.
We're using beautiful
soup for parsing here.
Third, we're going to select
repeated elements here.
And then fourth, we're going to
normalize the text on it.
So this works best when content
loads directly into the page,
meaning you can see it
from the view page source.
The syntax here is not
the point, it's the flow.
All right.
Okay, so we can follow the same
logic in R as well.
We have the URL here.
We're reading it into R here.
We're taking the page here.
We are parsing the tree here.
And then we are creating a text here
with a pipe logic.
But it follows the same kind of
syntax principles as
the Python version.
So embedded HTML tables are often
the best case scenario.
They're explicit, structured, and
relatively stable.
Many institutional sites quietly
expose high quality data this way.
Whenever possible, you should prefer
embedded tables over
custom scraping logic.
They break off often and require
fewer assumptions.
Here's two coding examples for it.
We're reading, so here we're looking
for the table, the first element,
same kind of process here.
We're working the page that's
written here, getting the table, and
selecting the first element.
But even without ABIs,
data is often paginated.
Pagination rules are part of the
data generating process.
They determine how much data you can
collect and often
how you can update it.
Missing a page usually
doesn't throw an error.
It suddenly removes observations.
That's one of the most dangerous
failure modes of scraping a topic.
[no speech detected]
The many data sets
require crawling links.
This is where scraping shifts from
download a page to
traverse a network.
So once you do this, logging becomes
essential because without logs, you
cannot tell where you visited,
what you skipped and what fails.
This is a Python example here where
we are looping
over hyper references.
We're finding all the values here.
And then here the same thing are we
have our page elements and we're
pulling the attributes here.
Trying to make sure you always
normalize and de-duplicate URLs when
you work out something like that.
So scraping is an interaction,
non-misterraction.
Code practice includes rate
limiting, user agent headers, error
handling, and saving raw responses.
This is the API lecture,
we're going to see as well.
But then we'll look
at the same for it.
But stability, reproducibility
matter more than speed in this case.
[no speech detected]
So some of the highest quality web
data come from boring places.
Things like local governments,
professional associations,
or doing work filings, or
posting in static reports.
These sites change slowly and
publish information
because they're required to.
Not because they're
optimizing engagement.
[no speech detected]
So boring websites tend to have
clean HTML, minimal JavaScript, and
predictable layouts.
If you care about
longitudinal data, boring is good.
Flashing websites can break much
more easily, but
boring is very predictable.
[no speech detected]
So this is not optional for your
workflow when you're
doing web scraping.
Every scraper workflow
needs good documentation.
Should report source URLs, access
dates, processing logic,
and no gaps or failures.
If someone cannot restructure data
set how it was built, then the data
set is solved as incomplete.
[no speech detected]
So here's the takeaways.
You want to understand
the structure before coding.
Start simple.
Treat scraping as measurement.
Expect breakage and document it.
And it's going to follow the same as
the API lecture that
we're going to see as well.
[no speech detected]
So there's a couple
things to keep in mind.
You should think a lot about where
to buy into web collected data.
So what kinds of information are
organizations, for example,
required to publish and how might
they obfuscate certain information.
Which sites are trustworthy for
scraping purposes?
So for example, some of my Wikipedia
is frequently scraped.
Users can edit it.
When I was in high school Wikipedia
was not seen as a legitimate source.
And it's gained a lot more
credibility, I
think, since that period.
But we can see that political
operative maybe are changing web
data constantly to try to alter
how candidates are viewed.
So even in some education, maybe
it's not
particularly trustworthy on it.
And then what assumptions
are hidden in the layout.
It's going to keep in mind.
But just keep in as a total for
these three discussion questions.
Just remember that
scraping is not neutral.
Haze to the time is going to reflect
institutional incentives and
audience priorities.
And understanding those choices is
part of doing serious
social data analysis.